Guide to the Franz R. and Kathryn M. Stenzel Collection of Western American Art
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Other Artwork, 1790-1966; Series IV; 24.06; (15 boxes)
  - MEISSNER, [----?]
    - [Procession of women carrying food, four people riding a donkey, and a man following with a violin.] Pen-and-ink drawing, 13.3 x 22.9 cm., 1889 (Box 39, Folder 766)
  - METZ, C.
    - "The Launch of the North West America at Nootka Sound. Being the first Vessel that was ever built in that part of the Globe." Engraving, 22.3 x 25.5 cm., 1790 (Box 39, Folder 767)
      "R. Pollard, Sculpt."
  - MEYER, RICHARD MAX
    - [Native American camp on the Puyallup River, Wn.] Watercolor and gouache, 51.3 x 71.6 cm., 1894
    - [Skeleton and muscles of a right hand.] Watercolor and gouache, 27.5 x 16.4 cm., 1883 (Box 39, Folder 768)
    - "Skelett des Menschen." Pen-and-ink drawing, 25.6 x 20.2 cm. (Box 39, Folder 769)
      With notes identifying the skeleton in German
  - MOODY, E.
    - "Gentlemens residences being the style of private dwelling houses in Valparaiso. View from the rear of the American Consul's House." Watercolor and pen-and-ink, 10.2 x 21.9 cm. (Box 39, Folder 770)
  - MORAN, THOMAS
    - See also Thomas Moran's work in Series V, box 49, folder 978
    - "The Castle Geyser, Upper Geyser Basin, Yellowstone National Park." Chromolithograph, 24.5 x 35.1 cm., 1874 (Box 40, Folder 771)
      Reproduced and published by L. Prang & Co., Boston, Mass.
    - "The Grand Canon, Yellowstone." Chromolithograph, 24.5 x 35.2 cm. (Box 40, Folder 772)
    - "The Great Blue Spring of the Lower Geyser Basin Yellowstone." Chromolithograph, 24.3 x 35.1 cm., 1875 (Box 40, Folder 773)
    - "Great Falls of Snake River, Idaho Territory." Chromolithograph, 24.7 x 35.4 cm., 1876 (Box 40, Folder 774)
    - "Head of Yellowstone River." Chromolithograph, 24.6 x 35.3 cm., 1876 (Box 40, Folder 775)
    - [Hunting scene.] Etching, plate mark 11.3 x 18.1 cm. on sheet 20 x 27.6 cm., 1883 (Box 40, Folder 776)
    - "Lower Yellowstone Range." Chromolithograph, 24 x 35.2 cm., n.d. (Box 40, Folder 777)
      Reproduced and published by L. Prang &Co., Boston, Mass.
    - "The Mountain of the Holy Cross, Colorado." Chromolithograph, 35.4 x 24.6 cm., n.d. (Box 40, Folder 778)
    - [The Mountain of the Holy Cross, Colorado.] Print, 77 x 53.6 cm., 1888
    - [Native Americans in front of the cliffs of Green River, Utah?] Chromolithograph, 30.5 x 17.6 cm., n.d. (Box 40, Folder 779)
    - "Summit of the Sierras, Nevada." Chromolithograph, 36 x 24.8 cm., 1875 (Box 40, Folder 780)
    - "The Upper Yellowstone Falls." Etching, 31.7 x 23.9 cm., 1875 (Box 40, Folder 781)
      D. Appleton & Co., Washington, D.C.
    - "Valley of Babbling Waters, Southern Utah." Chromolithograph, 24.4 x 35.2 cm. (Box 40, Folder 782)
    - "Yellowstone Lake." Chromolithograph, 23.7 x 34.7 cm., 1875 (Box 40, Folder 783)
  - MOSER, JAMES HENRY
    - [Town meeting.] Watercolor over pencil, 26.8 x 37.1 cm., 1892 (Box 40, Folder 784)
  - N. CURRIER
    - "The French Corvette L'Astrolabe Quitting the Polar Sea." Chromolithograph, 36.3 x 48.4 cm., n.d. (Box 40, Folder 785)
      "No. 3580 Lith. & Pub. by N. Currier"
    - "Not Caught. There is Many a Slip Between the Cup and Lip." Lithograph, 46.6 x 61 cm.
      "Lith. & Pub. by N. Currier."
    - "Shipscene I. Departure. American Whaler." Chromolithograph, 36.3 x 48.2 cm. (Box 40, Folder 786)
      "No. 3540 Lith. & Pub. by N. Currier"
  - N., K. W.
    - [Lighthouse.] Pencil drawing, 18.1 x 27.1 cm., 1890 Jul 4 (Box 40, Folder 787)
  - NARJOT, ERNEST
    See: Joseph Langer, box 38, folder 748
  - NAST, [----?]
    - [Street scene.] Oil painting on paper, 11.5 x 10.7 cm., n.d. (Box 40, Folder 788)
  - NICHOLL, THOMAS JEFF
    - "Chautauqua." Wash and crayon over pencil, 17.8 x 26.8 cm., 1880 (Box 40, Folder 789)
    - "In Wyoming." Pen-and-ink and wash drawing, 17.8 x 27 cm., 1884 (Box 40, Folder 790)
    - [Man fishing on pier with another man in rowboat on lake.] Watercolor, 16.1 x 23.9 cm., n.d. (Box 40, Folder 791)
    - "On the Great Whiteway." Watercolor, 22.8 x 34.7 cm., n.d. (Box 40, Folder 792)
    - "Silver Lake." Pen-and-ink and watercolor, 17.8 x 27 cm., 1884 (Box 40, Folder 793)
    - "Steamer Jamestown at Kents dock Chautauqua." Pen-and-ink and wash drawing, 17.7 x 27.2 cm., 1881 (Box 40, Folder 794)
  - NIXON, J.
    - [Men and a woman watching a horse race.] Colored lithograph, 15.8 x 21.6 cm. (Box 40, Folder 795)
  - O., G. S.
    - "'Maxwell Land Grant and Railway Co.' Engineer's Camp on Summit of Longé Cañon and Canadian River Cañon, Raton Mountains." Watercolor, 12.6 x 25.1 cm. on sheet 24.8 x 33.5 cm., 1871 Sep (Box 41, Folder 796)
  - O'CONNOR, [----?]
    - "Indian Village." Colored etching, visible image 16 x 11.4 cm. (Box 41, Folder 797)
    - [Totem poles.] Colored etching, visible image 15.3 x 20.7 cm., n.d. (Box 41, Folder 798)
  - OERTEL, [JOHANNES ADAM SIMON]
    - "Hambletonian, The Property of W. M. Rysdyk, Esq." Chromolithograph, 52 x 63.7 cm., 1865
      "Endicott & Co. Chromo-Lith. ... Entered according to Act of Congress AD 1865 by Brewster & Co. ..."
  - OTTINGER, GEORGE M. (GEORGE MARTIN)
    - "Idaho 'Fast' Line." Watercolor, 24.6 x 33.6 cm., n.d. (Box 41, Folder 799)
    - "Salmon fishing in Columbia Cascades." Pencil drawing, 29.8 x 21.7 cm., 1890 Jun 18 (Box 41, Folder 800)
  - PARROTT, WILLIAM S.
    - [Mountain.] Oil painting, 11.4 x 19.2 cm. (Box 41, Folder 801)
  - PEIRCE, E. L.
    - "Mount Hood." Etching, plate mark 9.2 x 14.7 cm. on sheet 22.9 x 29.6 cm., n.d. (Box 41, Folder 802)
      "E. L. Peirce" written at bottom left. "Wm. Keith" written at bottom right
  - PLONNIN, N.
    - [War Bonnet.] Pastel, 47.4 x 30.8 cm., 1902 (Box 41, Folder 803)
      Signed. Title from Sotheby's auction catalog, June 24, 1980: Fine American Western Paintings: The Collection of Dr. and Mrs. Franz Stenzel
  - PLOWMAN, GEORGE TAYLOR
    - "Mount Hood, Oregon." Etching, plate mark 20.7 x 31.4 cm. on sheet 26.8 x 36.7 cm., [1925] (Box 41, Folder 804)
  - POWELL, [----?]
    - "'Eagle Speaker' Blackfeet." Pencil drawing with pastel, visible image 33.4 x 25.7 cm., n.d. (Box 41, Folder 805)
  - PRICE, CLAYTON SUMNER
    - [Cattle drive.] Offset lithograph, 32.4 x 42.7 cm., 1906 (Box 41, Folder 806)
    - "Rainy Day." Oil painting, 59 x 75 cm. in frame 67 x 83 cm., n.d.
  - PROCTOR, ALEXANDER PHIMISTER
    - "Measurements of Mustangs made by A. Phimister Proctor, Kings Ranch - Texas, 1938-39." Sketchbook, 22.5 x 30.4 cm.
      Stored in: Oversize box 56, folder 1103
    - [Mountain peak.] Oil painting, 15 x 18 cm. in frame 21 x 24 cm., 1919
    - [Mountain sheep.] Etching, plate mark 26.2 x 28.8 cm. on sheet 36.6 x 37.3 cm.
  - R., M. DE B.
    - [Lake scene with ferry.] Watercolor, 29.7 x 22.5 cm., n.d. (Box 41, Folder 807)
  - R., R. B.
    - "Rockland, Del Norte Co. Cal." Watercolor, 22.3 x 28.7 cm. (Box 41, Folder 808)
  - RE[-----?], H.
    - "Fleet maneuvers, U.S. Navy." Watercolor, 21.7 x 27 cm., n.d. (Box 41, Folder 809)
  - REDWOOD, ALLEN CHRISTIAN
    - "Great Expectations - Geo. E. Starr Booming Washington Territory." Pen-and-ink and wash drawing, 14 x 22.8 cm. (Box 41, Folder 810)
      Signed "A.C.R." Two drawings of mules on verso in pen-and-ink and wash
    - "John - Spokane buck. Spokane Falls." Watercolor, 22.5 x 14 cm., 1882 Jul (Box 41, Folder 811)
      Signed "A.C.R." Two drawings of a Native American and "Captain Jack" dated 1882 Jul and Aug on verso in pen-and-ink
    - "N.P.R.R. Construction - Lower Cascades, W.T." Pen-and-ink drawing with wash, 22.8 x 14 cm., 1882 Jul (Box 41, Folder 812)
      Signed "A.C.R." Preliminary watercolor sketch on verso of a mountain scene
  - REES PRINT & LITHO. CO.
    - "Abraham Lincoln's Return Home After His Successful Campaign for the Presidency of the United States, in October, 1860." Chromolithograph, 50.4 x 63.2 cm., n.d.
  - REINAGLE, G. P.
    - "The East India Ship Duke of Buccleuch, (Captn. Alexr. Henning,) in a Hurricane off the Mauritius, attempting to wear." Colored engraving, 48.6 x 62.6 cm., 1836
      Published by Ackermann & Co.
  - REMINGTON, FREDERIC
    - [Cow branding.] Photogravure, 30.5 x 40.7 cm. (Box 41, Folder 813)
    - [Gold miners.] Photogravure, 30.4 x 40.6 cm., n.d. (Box 41, Folder 814)
    - "Mule Train Crossing the Sierras." Photogravure, 30.5 x 40.7 cm., n.d. (Box 41, Folder 815)
  - RICHARDSON, J.
    - [Seated old Native American man with woven basket to the right, painted box to his left.] Watercolor, 34.3 x 26.5 cm. (Box 42, Folder 816)
  - RILEY, G. B.
    - [Seal of the City of Seattle.] Watercolor, 25.3 x 17.7 cm., 1896 (Box 42, Folder 817)
      Signed. "Original drawing from which 1st seal of the city of Seattle was made. Mrs. G. B. Riley."
  - ROCKWELL, CLEVELAND
    - "In the Rocky Mountains, Canada." Oil painting, 84.6 x 151 cm. in frame 106 x 172 cm., 1892
  - ROGERS, WALTER S.
    - "At the time the marksman could not have been more than 15 feet away." Watercolor and gouache, 30.3 x 21.4 cm. on sheet 50.5 x 37.8 cm. (Box 42, Folder 818)
      Signed. Illustration for Pioneer Boys of the Yellowstone chapter 29, galley 70
    - "A large section of the bank of the river, where they found it so wet in passing had suddenly let go." Watercolor and gouache, 31.7 x 20.2 cm. on sheet 50.8 x 37.6 cm., [ca. 1916] (Box 42, Folder 819)
      Signed. Illustration for Pioneer Boys of the Columbia, chapter 31
    - "Before them they saw a mighty column of steaming water gushing fully a hundred feet up into the air." Watercolor, 36 x 23.8 cm., [ca. 1915] (Box 42, Folder 820)
      Signed. Illustration for Pioneer Boys of the Yellowstone
    - [Boys on horseback fleeing stampeding herd of buffalo in a storm.] Watercolor and gouache, 42 x 26.8 cm on sheet 50.2 x 37.8 cm. (Box 42, Folder 821)
      Signed. Illustration for unidentified book
  - [ROLLINS, WARREN ELIPHALET]
    - [Man fishing, with mountain in background.] Watercolor, 10.6 x 19.3 cm. (Box 42, Folder 822)
      Signed W. E. R.
  - RUSSELL, CHARLES M.
    - "Breaking Camp." Color print, 15.2 x 20.2 cm., 1905 (Box 42, Folder 823)
      "Ridgely Calendar Co. Great Falls"
    - "The Challenge." Color halftone, 22.8 x 30.3 cm., n.d. (Box 42, Folder 824)
    - "Here's hoping the worst end of your trail is behind you..." Color print, 20.7 x 28.3 cm., 1962 (Box 42, Folder 825)
      With printed note signed by Nancy C. Russell indicating that Charles Russell made the sketch for their Christmas card and thanking them for the messages of condolence
    - "Just a little..." series. Color prints, 27.5 x 17.6 cm. and smaller (Box 42, Folder 826)
      R. R. Doubleday and Sid Willis. Titles: "Just a Little Sunshine," "Just a Little Rain," "Just a Little Pain," "Just a Little Pleasure"
    - [Native American war party on the plains.] Color print, 50.2 x 71 cm.
      Advertisement for "John Hauenstein Company 'Brewers and Bottlers since 1864' New Ulm, Minnesota"
    - [Portfolio of sixteen prints copyright The Leader Co., Great Falls, Mont.] 35.4 x 27 cm. and smaller, 1927 (Box 42, Folder 827-828)
    - "Tight Dally and Loose Latigo." Color halftone, 22.8 x 30.3 cm. (Box 42, Folder 829)
    - [Postcards of Russell artwork.] Color prints, 1904-26, n.d.
    - [Postcards of Russell artwork.] Prints on silk, n.d.
  - SADAR, A.
    - [Ship frozen in harbor, with igloos and dogsled in foreground.] Oil painting on stretcher, 55.3 x 86 cm.
  - SCHAFER, FREDERICK FERDINAND
    - "Sunset on Castle Rock on Columbia Riv. Oregon." Oil painting on stretcher, 31 x 51 cm., n.d.
  - SCHEUERLE, JOSEPH
    - "White Grass, Blackfeet Indian Scout. Glacier National Park, Montana. See America First." Chromolithograph, 32.8 x 22.7 cm., 1914 (Box 42, Folder 830)
  - SCHOONOVER, FRANK EARLE
    - "Old Rogers' fierce eyes glittered as he whispered the one word, 'Treasure!'" Oil painting, 90 x 75.6 cm. in frame 98 x 83.4 cm., n.d.
      Original illustration from Blackbeard Buccaneer by Ralph D. Paine. Artist attribution from Sotheby's auction catalog, June 24, 1980: Fine American Western Paintings: The Collection of Dr. and Mrs. Franz Stenzel
  - SCHUMACHER & ETTLINGER
    - "A House at Orange, N.J. Joseph A. Stark, Architect, New York." Chromolithograph, 55.9 x 40.6 cm., 1886 Jun (Box 42, Folder 831)
      "Supplement to the Scientific American - Architects and Builders Edition."
  - SELTZER, O. C. (OLAF C.)
    - [Wagon train.] Color print, 30.4 x 40.5 cm. (Box 42, Folder 832)
      Copyright General Mills, Inc.
  - SHEFFERS, PETER WINTHROP
    - "Trappers Peak, Bitterroot Mountains, Montana." Oil painting, 19.6 x 26.3 cm., 1941 Jun (Box 43, Folder 833)
  - SHRAPNEL, EDWARD SCROPE
    - [View of Native American canoe on water with two figures in canoe.] Oil painting, 14.7 x 32.7 cm., 1906 (Box 43, Folder 834)
  - SIMPSON, WILLIAM
    - "Steamer Spokane Approaching Texas Ferry." Pencil drawing, 14 x 21.4 cm., n.d. (Box 43, Folder 835)
  - SNOW, J. H.
    - [Native Americans by a lake.] Oil painting, 21.9 x 28 cm., 1883 (Box 43, Folder 836)
  - SPADE, E. M.
    - [Horse.] Pen-and-ink drawing, 16.5 x 22.8 cm. (Box 43, Folder 837)
  - STANDINGS, WM.
    - [Preaching to drunks.] Lithograph, 28.5 x 55.7 cm., [1960] (Box 43, Folder 838)
      Copyright 1960 Trail Side Galleries Dick Flood Idaho Falls, Idaho
  - [STANLEY, JOHN MIX]
    - See also John Mix Stanley's work in Series V, box 50, folder 989-996
    - [Self-portrait, sketching by a stream.] Oil painting, 49 x 38.7 cm in frame 67.8 x 57.5 cm., n.d.
      Attributed to John Mix Stanley
      Stored in: Artstore, folder 1258
  - STERN, ALEXANDER
    - "Arizona Indian Girl." Etching, plate mark 23.9 x 16.2 on sheet 39.8 x 32.8 cm. (Box 43, Folder 839)
  - STONER, J. J.
    - "Bird's Eye View of the Town of Nantucket State of Massachusetts. Looking Southwest. 1881." Lithograph, 52.2 x 74.7 cm.
      Beck & Pauli Lith. Milwaukee, Wis.
  - STRONG, H. A.
    "Interior of Fort Garry. A vanished scene in the early History of our Country." Chromolithograph, 58 x 85.5 cm.
    "The Burland Lithographic Co. Montreal"
  - STRONG, JOSEPH DWIGHT
    - [Islanders canoeing in Hawaii.] Watercolor, 32.7 x 50 cm., 1888 (Box 43, Folder 840)
  - STUART, JAMES EVERETT
    - "Crater Lake, looking North from the Surface of the Water Aug 31 1882." Oil painting on wood, 35.6 x 55.7 cm. (Box 43, Folder 841)
    - "Pilot Rock located on the Summit of Siskiyou Mountains." Oil painting, 14.5 x 29.5 cm. in frame 27.5 x 42.5 cm.
      Signed. "To very good friend Geo. W. Steel, compliments of J. E. Stuart" written on verso
      Stored in: Artstore folder 1259
  - SWAIM, ROBERT
    - [Lake scene with two figures in a canoe, and two figures on a dock.] Watercolor, 20 x 27.6 cm., 1906 (Box 43, Folder 842)
    - [Native American woman with horse.] Oil painting on stretcher, 30.5 x 24 cm.
    - [Four photographs of Swaim artwork(?), two depicting miners, one of skiers outside a small cabin, and another of a man fishing in a stream] 35.3 x 27.8 cm. and smaller (Box 43, Folder 843)
      One of the photographs is hand-colored
  - SWIFT, THOMAS
    - [Fort in spring, with figures on horseback.] Oil painting, 27 x 63.5 cm. in frame 37.5 x 74.5 cm., 1904
    - [Fort.] Oil painting, 26.5 x 63.3 cm. in frame 37.6 x 74.5 cm., 1904
      Title on verso illegible. Signed
  - [T., N. P.?]
    - "Chief Richards [illegible]" Oil painting, 30 x 25.8 cm., n.d. (Box 43, Folder 844)
  - TILBURN, E. O.
    - [Battery Park, New York City.] Oil painting on stretcher, 56.5 x 91.5 cm., 1897
  - TOFT, PETER PETERSON
    - "Falls Pelouse River." Watercolor, 15.1 x 23.2 cm. on sheet 26.6 x 35.4 cm., [ca. 1858] (Box 43, Folder 845)
    - "My Mining Cabin on Elk Creek Montana." Watercolor, 23.1 x 31.8 cm., 1866 (Box 43, Folder 846)
    - "O.S.N. Route. Cape Horn [Dalles - Celilo R.R.] looking east." Watercolor, 34.4 x 50.7 cm., 1862 (Box 43, Folder 847)
      Oregon Steam Navigation Route
    - "Spokane Falls W.T." Watercolor, 15 x 23.2 on sheet 26.3 x 35 cm., [ca. 1852] (Box 44, Folder 848)
    - "Three Mile Prairie, Bitterroot." Watercolor, 14.8 x 23.2 cm. on sheet 26.5 x 34.8 cm., n.d. (Box 44, Folder 849)
      Signed. Caption on back cut off, affecting text
    - [Train going across trestle bridge, with mountain in background.] Watercolor, 34.3 x 51 cm.
      Stored in: Oversize box 61, folder 1159
    - [View of Wind Mountain from the left bank of Columbia. Str. James P. Flint. looking downstream.] Watercolor, 34.2 x 50.9 cm.
  - TORGERSON, WILLIAM
    - "Striden Emellan 'Monitor' och Merrimac 1862." Chromolithograph, 55.2 x 76 cm., 1877
      "Shober & Carqueville Props. Chicago Lith. Co."
  - TOVEY, GEORGE H.
    - [Bastion of fort.] Watercolor, 20.4 x 52.1 cm., 1892
  - TOWNSHEND, A. L.
    - "Un Gaucho de Mendoza." Watercolor, 32.1 x 36.9 cm., 1889 (Box 44, Folder 850)
  - TUKE, H. S.
    - "All Hands to the Pump." Color print, 45.5 x 35.8 cm., 1905 (Box 44, Folder 851)
      "American Colortype Co. N.Y. & Chi."
  - VALLEY, J. F.
    - [Two Navy vessels, British and Spanish (?) off an unidentified coast.] Watercolor, visible image 41 x 65.5 cm.
  - VANDERHOOF, C. A.
    - [Haying scene, bonanza farming.] Pen-and-ink drawing, 28.3 x 40.7 cm. (Box 44, Folder 852)
    - "Platoon of 18 Self Binders." Pen-and-ink and watercolor, 28.8 x 41.6 cm. (Box 44, Folder 853)
      Signed. For "A Grain of Wheat"
  - WADDINGHAM, JOHN ALFRED
    "Steel Bridge over the Willamette." Watercolor, visible image 35.7 x 50.8 cm.
    Signed. Label on verso: "Second prizewinner, Oregon State Fair, 55."
  - WALKER, JAMES
    - "Gettysburg. Repulse of Longstreet's Assault." Lithograph, 61 x 106 cm., 1876
  - WARRE, HENRY JAMES
    - "The American Village." Colored lithograph, 35.7 x 45.5 cm., n.d. (Box 44, Folder 854)
      "H. J. Warre del. Dickinson & Co. Lith."
    - "The Rocky Mountains." Colored lithograph, 36.4 x 56.6 cm., n.d. (Box 44, Folder 855)
    - "The Rocky Mountains from the Columbia River Looking N.W." Colored lithograph, 34.6 x 48.3 cm., 1846 (Box 44, Folder 856)
  - WAY, CHARLES JONES
    - "Montana." Watercolor, 10.6 x 17.5 cm., [1894?] Aug 31 (Box 44, Folder 857)
    - "Room No. 4." Watercolor, 24.1 x 30.4 cm. (Box 44, Folder 858)
    - [Street scene.] Watercolor, 27 x 20.3 cm. (Box 44, Folder 859)
    - [View of plains with mountains in background.] Watercolor, 22.7 x 30.3 cm. (Box 44, Folder 860)
  - WEISE, A. L.
    - "View of the Ground and Buildings, International Exhibition, Fairmount Park, Philadelphia 1876." Tinted lithograph, 54 x 69 cm.
  - WELCH, L.
    - [Mt. Hood with woman and girl in foreground.] Oil painting, 20.6 x 20.8 cm. (Box 44, Folder 861)
  - WEST, [ALINE?]
    - [Cowboy.] Pastel, 53.3 x 25.2 cm., 1911 (Box 44, Folder 862)
  - WEST, LEVON
    - "Hunting Strays." Etching, 21.9 x 35 cm. on sheet 29.1 x 44.6 cm., n.d. (Box 44, Folder 863)
      Signed. "3."
    - "Mountain Sleet." Etching, 24.6 x 30.3 cm. (Box 44, Folder 864)
      Signed. "1/100"
  - WIEGHORST, OLAF
    - [Two studies of Native American men's heads.] Pen-and-ink, pencil and crayon sketches, 29.5 x 22.2 cm. (Box 44, Folder 865)
  - WILLEY, [----?]
    - [Riverbank.] Watercolor, 25.1 x 35.5 cm. (Box 44, Folder 866)
  - WILLOUGHBY, ADELINE CHENEY
    - "Solitude." Pencil drawing, 27 x 33.9 cm. (Box 44, Folder 867)
      Signed "A.C.W." Mat title: "Port Townsend, W.T."
  - WIMAR, CARL
    - "Die Führer des Überfall's." Engraving, plate mark 13.9 x 17.4 cm. on sheet 21.8 x 28.7 cm., n.d. (Box 44, Folder 868)
      "Druck u. Verlag d. Englischen Kunstanstalt v. A.H. Payne Leipzig &Dresden"
    - "Die Rückzug." Engraving, 13.5 x 18.5 cm. on sheet 22 x 28.5 cm., n.d.
  - WIRE, MELVILLE T.
    - "Celilo Indian Village." Etching, plate mark 20 x 30 cm. on sheet 29 x 37.5 cm. (Box 44, Folder 869)
      Signed. Accompanied by advertisement for Wire's etchings
    - "Wallula Cliffs on the Columbia." Etching, plate mark 20.2 x 33 cm. on sheet 27.8 x 29.3 cm., n.d. (Box 44, Folder 870)
  - WISE, JOHN C.
    - "Execution of the Thirty-Eight Sioux Indians at Mankato, Minnesota, December 26, 1862." Chromolithograph, 42 x 52 cm., 1883 (Box 45, Folder 871)
      The Milwaukee Litho. & Engr. Co.
  - WOOD, CHARLES ERSKINE SCOTT
    - [Harbor.] Watercolor, 14.5 x 27.7 cm., n.d. (Box 45, Folder 872)
    - [Lake.] Watercolor, 25.4 x 35.6 cm., n.d. (Box 45, Folder 873)
    - [Landscape with hills.] Watercolor, 29.9 x 45.6 cm. (Box 45, Folder 874)
    - [Pond.] Watercolor, 30.5 x 40.7 cm., 1896 (Box 45, Folder 875)
    - [Sailing ship - Columbia River.] Watercolor, visible image 20.2 x 26.6 cm. (Box 45, Folder 876)
    - "Skippanawin." Pen-and-ink drawing, 18 x 30.5 cm., 1883 (Box 45, Folder 877)
    - [Waterfront with sailing ships in the distance.] Watercolor, visible image 16.3 x 34.5 cm. (Box 45, Folder 878)
  - YELLAND, RAYMOND DABB
    - "Astoria, Oregon." Pencil drawing, 8.8 x 12.7 cm., 1880 Jun 17 (Box 45, Folder 879)
    - [View of a fort by a river.] Pencil drawing, 9 x 12.5 cm., n.d. (Box 45, Folder 880)
  - ZIEGLER, HENRY
    - [Two cowboys and a herd of cattle.] Etching, plate mark 17.3 x 22.6 cm. on sheet 25.1 x 32.9 cm. (Box 45, Folder 881)
  - ZINSTRY, A. L.
    - "Skidmore fountain, Portland." Watercolor, 23 x 30 cm. on sheet 30.4 x 37.5 cm., 1889 (Box 45, Folder 882)
  - UNIDENTIFIED
    - "Astoria, on the Columbia River." Colored engraving, visible image 12.5 x 20.5 cm., n.d. (Box 45, Folder 883)
    - "Australicher Begräbnissplatz." Chromolithograph, 21 x 26 cm., n.d. (Box 45, Folder 884)
    - [Award certificate for Lewis and Clark Centennial American Pacific Exposition and Oriental Fair.] Tinted lithograph, 62.3 x 48 cm., 1905
      "Bushong & Co. Portland Or."
    - "Baron Wogan am Todespfahl." Chromolithograph, 22.8 x 31.6 cm., n.d. (Box 45, Folder 885)
    - "The Battle of Waterloo." Pen-and-ink drawing, 11.5 x 16.2 cm. (Box 45, Folder 886)
    - [The Beaver towing The Columbia.] Watercolor, visible image 14 x 31.5 cm., n.d. (Box 45, Folder 887)
      Title from appraiser's notes
    - "Le Bison." Colored engraving, 10.2 x 11.3 cm., n.d. (Box 45, Folder 888)
    - [Cabin by a lake.] Pen-and-ink drawing, 11.1 x 17.7 cm. (Box 45, Folder 889)
    - [Cabin in the mountains.] Colored etching, 15.4 x 20 cm. on sheet 20.4 x 28.7 cm., n.d. (Box 45, Folder 890)
      Name below image in pencil is illegible
    - "The Caroline Steam Boat Precipitated over the Falls of Niagara Dec. 29 1837." Colored lithograph, 19.6 x 30.1 cm. (Box 45, Folder 891)
    - "Catholic Institutions of Spokane Falls, W.T." Lithograph, 32 x 48.2 cm., n.d. (Box 45, Folder 892)
    - "Chinamen's Shanties." Two views, one in watercolor, one in oil, 16 x 19.5 cm. and smaller (Box 45, Folder 893)
    - "The City of Richmond, Indiana." Tinted lithograph, 70.5 x 101 cm., 1884
      "C.H. Bailey & Co., Pub." Printed by J.W.C. Gilman & Co."
    - "Conglomerate Hills Near Ft. Wilkins." Colored lithograph, 13.4 x 21.5 cm., n.d. (Box 45, Folder 894)
      Ackermann lith. N.Y.
    - "Custer's Last Fight." Chromolithograph, 79 x 106 cm. in frame 91.5 x 118.5 cm., 1896
      Adolphus Busch, St. Louis. Title continues: "The Original Painting has been Presented to the Seventh Regiment U.S. Cavalry by Anheuser-Busch, St. Louis, Missouri, U.S.A. World's Largest Brewery"
    - "Democratic National Candidates. For President Grover Cleveland, of New York. For Vice President Allen G. Thurman of Ohio." Lithograph, 55.6 x 72 cm., [1884]
      "Sent by Courier-Journal, Louisville, Ky."
    - [Farm house.] Watercolor, 35.5 x 50.8 cm. (Box 45, Folder 895)
    - [Farmstead.] Pencil drawing, 30.4 x 45.5 cm., n.d. (Box 45, Folder 896)
    - "A Fast Clerk." Chromolithograph, 24.2 x 18 cm., n.d. (Box 45, Folder 897)
      Cartoon of a man bowling with poem "A Fast Clerk" below
    - "Fort D.A. Russell, W.T." Watercolor, 34.5 x 43.1 cm., n.d. (Box 45, Folder 898)
      Wyoming Territory